In the last video,
上个视频里
we learnt how to create NumPy arrays by converting
我们学习了创建 NumPy 数组的方法
existing array like objects such as Python lists,
即用 NumPy 函数 array
using NumPy's array function.
转换 Python 列表等已有的类数组对象 从而进行创建
But one great time saving feature of NumPy is
但 NumPy 之所以能节省大量时间 原因之一就是
its ability to generate specific kinds of NumPy arrays from nothing,
它能从无到有地生成特定的 NumPy 数组
using just one line of code.
全程只需使用一行代码
Here, we will see a few of the most useful builtin functions for generating Numpy arrays.
现在我们来讲几种最实用的内置 NumPy 数组生成函数
Let's start by creating a NumPy array of zeroes with a shape that we specify.
我们先创建一个由 0 组成的 NumPy 数组 并指定其形状属性 shape
We can do this by using NumPy's zeros function.
为此 我们可以用 NumPy 的函数 zeros
This function takes as an argument the shape of the array you want to create.
函数参数就是你想生成的数组形状
Passing in the tuple (3,4) gives us a 3 by 4 array of zeros.
输入元组 (3 , 4) 我们就得到了一个由 0 组成的 3 x 4 数组
By default, this creates an array with the data type float 64.
这个数组的数据类型默认为 64 位浮点型
If you want to use a different data type,
如果想用其它数据类型
you can change this with the keyword dtype.
可以用关键字 dtype 进行更改
Similarly, we can create a NumPy array of ones using this function,
同理 我们可以用这个函数来创建由 1 组成的 NumPy 数组
which also takes shape as an argument.
该函数的参数也是数组形状
In addition to ones and zeros,
除了 ones 和 zeros
you can create an array filled with any constant value using the full function.
还可以用函数 full 来创建由任意常数组成的数组
This takes two arguments,
函数需要两个参数
a shape for the array and the constant you want to fill it with.
一个是数组的形状 一个是你想填充的常数
The full function by default creates an array
函数 full 创建的数组
with a data type of the value you inputted as a constant.
其数据类型默认与你输入的常数值一样
Here, since we used the Integer 5 as our constant,
由于这里用整数 5 作为输入常数
this generated an array with the dtype int64.
所以生成的数组 dtype 为 64 位整数
Use the key word dtype to specify otherwise.
使用关键词 dtype 可以指定其它类型
A fundamental array in Linear Algebra is the identity matrix.
线性代数有一种基础数组叫单位矩阵
A matrix is just another term used to describe
矩阵这个术语
a two dimensional array with rows and columns.
其实指的就是横纵排列的二维数组
And, an identity matrix is
单位矩阵
just a square shaped matrix that has ones along its main diagonal,
其实就是一个方形的矩阵 其主对角线上的值都为 1
and zeros everywhere else.
其它位置的值则都为 0
NumPy's eye function can be used to create this.
我们可以用 NumPy 的函数 eye 来创建该矩阵
Since all identity matrices are square,
由于单位矩阵都是方形的
this only takes a single integer as an argument.
所以只接受一个单精度整数参数
Using 5 gives us a 5 x 5 identity matrix.
输入 5 我们就得到了一个 5 x 5 的单位矩阵
And its main diagonal which goes from the top
其从左上到右下的主对角线
left to the bottom right, is filled with ones.
都填着 0
We can also use Numpy's diag function to create a diagonal matrix.
我们还可以用 NumPy 的函数 diag 来生成对角矩阵
This function takes in as input a sequence of
这个函数的参数是一个数列
values to use as the main diagonal of a square matrix,
用于填充方形矩阵的主对角线
and fills in the rest with zeros.
其余位置的值则为 0
NumPy also has useful functions to generate arrays with specific numerical ranges.
NumPy 还有其它实用函数 可生成位于特定数值范围的数组
One useful one is arange,
其中一个函数叫 arange
which creates a one dimensional array of evenly spaced values within a given interval.
用于创建位于给定区间的等差数组
This takes three arguments: start, stop, and step.
函数有三个参数 起始值、终止值和步长
But we can still use this whether we want to specify one,
我们可以只指定一个参数
two or three arguments.
也可以指定两个或三个参数
Let's see each case.
我们逐个来讲
When only one integer is specified,
只指定一个整数时
arange uses this as a stop argument,
函数 arange 会把这个整数看作终止参数
and generates an array of integers from zero to that integer minus one.
生成一个范围在 0 和该整数减 1 之间的数组
The stop argument is exclusive,
因为终止值不会包括在内
which is why we need to subtract one.
所以范围需要减一
For example, arange 10 gives us an array from zero to 10 minus one which is nine.
比如 arange (10) 会生成一个范围在 0 到 10 - 1 之间的数组 也即范围在 0 到 9 之间的数组
When used with two arguments,
指定两个参数时
arange uses the first as a start argument,
arange 会用第一个参数作为起始值
and the second as a stop argument.
第二个参数作为终止值
The start is inclusive,
起始值包括在范围之内
and the stop is exclusive.
终止值则不包括在内
Arange (4,10) gives us an array from four to nine.
所以 arange (4 , 10) 生成的数组范围在 4 到 9 之间
When you use the three arguments,
指定三个参数时
arange generates an array from the first integer to the second minus one,
函数 arange 会生成一个数组 其范围在第一个整数与第二个整数减 1 的差之间
evenly spaced by the third.
其值与值的间隔则为第三个参数的值
This third argument, the step,
这第三个参数就是步长了
is the distance between any two values in this array.
即数组中任意两个相邻值的差
When we specified only one or two arguments in arange earlier,
如果像之前一样 在 arange 里只指定一个或两个参数
step defaulted to one.
步长会默认为 1
Even though NumPy's arange function allows for a non integer steps such as 0.3,
虽然 NumPy 的函数 arange 允许非整数步长 比如 0.3
the output is usually inconsistent due to finite floating point precision.
但因为浮点数精度有限 所以输出往往不等差
For this reason, when we want non integer steps,
因此 如果想用非整数步长
it's usually better to use a different NumPy function, linspace.
最好用别的 NumPy 函数 即 linspace
This takes three arguments, start, stop,
该函数也有三个输入参数 起始值、终止值和 n
and n. This returns n evenly spaced numbers from start to stop,
函数会返回 n 个范围在起始值和终止值之间的等差数字
both start and stop being inclusive.
其中起始值和终止值都包括在范围内
Unlike arange, Linspace requires at least two arguments for start and stop.
与 arange 不同 linspace 需要至少两个参数 即起始值和终止值
If n is not specified,
如果没有指定 n
it defaults to 50.
那 n 就默认为 50
Let's see some examples.
我们来看些例子
Here's a rank one array that has 10 numbers evenly spaced from zero to 25.
这是个秩为 1 的数组 共有 10 个等差数值 范围在 0 到 25 之间
Again, note that both the start and stop points are inclusive.
注意 起始值和终止值都包含在数组中
However, you can let the stop endpoint of the interval be
但如果你不想区间包含终止值
excluded just like it is in the arange function,
就跟函数 arange 一样
if you set the keyword endpoint to false like this.
那你可以像这样设关键字 endpoint 为 False
As you can see, because we have excluded the endpoint 25,
正如你所见 由于我们排除了终止值 25
the spacing between the values had to change in
所以在给定区间中 10 个数值为了等差
order to fit 10 evenly spaced numbers in the given interval.
自动做出了调整
So far, we've only used the functions arange and linspace to create rank 1 arrays.
到目前为止 我们只是用函数 arange 和 linspace 来创建秩为 1 的数组
However, we can use these functions to create rank 2 arrays of
但这两个函数也可以创建秩为 2 且形状任意的数组
any shape by combining them with NumPy's reshape function.
我们只需将这两个函数与 NumPy 函数 reshape 结合使用即可
This function converts any NumPy array into a specified shape.
函数 reshape 能将任意 NumPy 数组转换为特定的形状
It's important to note that the new shape specified here,
注意 这里指定的新形状
should be compatible with a number of elements in the array.
应与数组的元素数目兼容
For example, you can convert a rank one array
比如 你可以把具备 20 个元素且秩为 1 的数组转换为
with 20 elements into a 4 by 5 rank two array,
秩为 2 的 4 x 5 数组
or a 10 by 2 array,
或秩为 2 的 10 x 2 数组
since both of these rank two arrays still have 20 elements.
因为这两个秩为 2 的数组仍然有 20 个元素
However, you can't reshape this to a 5 by 5 array,
但你不能把数组的形状改成 5 x 5
since this rank two array would have 25 elements,
因为秩为 2 的 5 x 5 数组有 25 个元素
which is greater than the number of elements in the original NumPy array.
比原始 NumPy 数组的元素数目多
One great feature about NumPy is that some functions can also be applied as methods.
NumPy 有一个优点是 有些函数还能当方法用
This allows us to apply different functions in sequence,
因而我们可以在一行代码里
in just one line of code.
接连使用不同的函数
NumPy array methods are similar to
NumPy 的数组方法与
its attributes in that they are both applied using dot notation.
其属性类似 使用时也要用 “ . ”
Let's see how we can accomplish the same result as this example using one line of code.
我们来看怎么用一行代码取得这个例子的效果
This gives us the same result.
这效果是一样的
Notice that when using reshape as a method,
注意 在将 reshape 当方法用时
we don't need to pas in the array as an argument.
我们不需要把数组当参数输入进去
Similarly, we can also use reshape to create rank two arrays with the linspace function.
同理 我们可以用函数 linspace 和方法 reshape 来创建秩为 2 的数组
Lastly, we are going to create NumPy arrays that contain random numbers.
最后 我们要创建一些包含随机数的 NumPy 数组
Often in machine learning,
在机器学习中
you need to create random matrices.
经常有需要创建随机矩阵的时候
For example, when initializing the weights of a neural network,
比如初始化神经网络的权重
NumPy offers a variety of
NumPy 提供了许多随机函数
random functions to help us create random NumPy arrays of any shape.
供我们创建任意形状的随机 NumPy 数组
Let's start by using NumPy's random function to create an array of a given shape,
我们先用 NumPy 函数 random 生成一个给定形状的随机浮点数数组
with random floats between zero and one,
其范围在 0 和 1 之间
where zero is inclusive,
其中 0 包含在范围内
and one is exclusive.
1 则不包含在内
The following functions including this random function,
这个函数 random 以及接下来要介绍的其它函数
are contained in NumPy's random module.
都包含在 NumPy 的 random 模块中
So we type np.random to access this module,
所以我们要输入 np.random 来访问该模块
and then.random to access the function in the module.
再输入 .random 来访问模块里的函数
NumPy also let's us create NumPy arrays
我们还能用 NumPy 创建
that contain random integers within a particular interval.
位于特定区间内的随机整数 NumPy 数组
We can use the function randint to do this.
为此 我们可以用函数 randint
This takes three arguments, the lower bound,
该函数接受三个参数 下限 (闭区间)
inclusive, and the upper bound,
上限 (开区间)
exclusive, and the shape.
以及形状
In some cases, you may need to create NumPy arrays
有时候 你要创建的 NumPy 数组
with random numbers that satisfy certain statistical properties.
其随机数得具备特定的统计属性
For example, you may want the random numbers in the array to have an average of zero.
比如 数组随机数的平均值应为 0
NumPy allows you to create random arrays with
NumPy 允许你创建
numbers drawn from various probability distributions.
从各种概率分布取值的随机数组
The function np.random.normal for example,
比如 函数 np.random.normal
creates an array with the given shape that
在创建给定形状的数组时
contains random numbers picked from a normal distribution,
会从具有给定平均值和标准差的正态分布中
with a given mean and standard deviation.
随机取值
This creates a 1000 by 1000 array of
这样就创建了一个 1000 x 1000 的随机浮点数数组
random floats drawn from a normal distribution with the mean of zero,
其数值取自平均值为 0
and a standard deviation of 0.1.
标准差为 0.1 的正态分布
As we can see, the average of the random numbers in the array is very close to zeo,
正如我们所见 数组随机数的平均值非常接近 0
and the standard deviation is also very close to 0.1.
标准差也非常接近 0.1
Both the maximum and minimum values next are symmetric about zero, the average.
下面的最大值和最小值也相当对称 加起来很接近平均值 0
And we have about the same number of positive and negative integers.
而且正整数和负整数的数目也差不多